Council on Foreign Relations Digital Sound Recordings, 1953-1989: Finding Aid MC104.13
Public Policy Papers
- Series 1: Digital Sound Recordings, 1953-1989; 24 boxes
  - Implications of Recent Developments for the Future of the United Nations, 1957 December 4; Johnson, Joseph E. (Joseph Esrey), 1906-1990; Munro, Sir Leslie; 1 box (Box 735)
    MC104-92A
  - France's Thoughts on Recent Changes in the World and Steps to Forestall Impending Dangers, 1957 December 3; Pineau, Christian; Wriston, Henry M. (Henry Merritt), 1889-1978; 1 box (Box 735)
    MC104-92B
  - Rockefeller Report on Military Security, 1958 January 22; Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich), 1908-1979; Wriston, Henry M. (Henry Merritt), 1889-1978; 1 box (Box 735)
    MC104-93A
  - Soviet Submarine Capabilities and the NATO Alliance, 1958 January 27; Johnson, Joseph E. (Joseph Esrey), 1906-1990; Wright, Jerauld; 1 box (Box 735)
    MC104-93B
  - The Current Crisis in North Africa, 1958 February 21; Gross, Ernest A.; Slim, Mongi; 1 box (Box 735)
    MC104-94A
  - The International Political Strategy of the Soviet Union, 1958 February 27; Altschul, Frank, 1887-1981; Amory, Robert, Jr., 1915-1989; 1 box (Box 735)
    MC104-94B
  - Soviet-American Relations, 1958 March 10; Menshikov, Mikhail A.; Wriston, Henry M. (Henry Merritt), 1889-1978; 1 box (Box 735)
    MC104-95A
  - Foreign Policy Problems Facing the United States, 1958 March 24; Herter, Christian A.; McCloy, John J. (John Jay), 1895-1989; 1 box (Box 735)
    MC104-96A
  - Untitled, 1958 March 31; Bell, Elliott V.; Erhard, Ludwig; 1 box (Box 735)
    MC104-96B
  - Problems of Leadership in New African States, 1958 April 14; Heckscher, August, 1913-1997; Ward, Barbara, 1914-1981; 1 box (Box 735)
    MC104-97A
  - The Soviet Economic Offensive and the United States' Aid Program, (The United States and the Soviet Union 3), 1958 May 21; Dillon, C. Douglas (Clarence Douglas), 1909-2003; Gaither, Rowan H., Jr; 1 box (Box 735)
    MC104-97B
  - The Strategic Deterrent, 1958 April 16; Finletter, Thomas K. (Thomas Knight), 1893-1980; Power, Thomas S.; 1 box (Box 735)
    MC104-98A
  - Communist China and Free Asia, 1958 April 16; Armstrong, Hamilton Fish, 1893-1973; Grantham, Alexander, 1899-1978; 1 box (Box 735)
    MC104-98B
  - New Weapons and their Future Development, (The United States and the Soviet Union 1), 1958 April 21; Foster, William C. (William Chapman), 1897-1984; Gaither, Rowan H., Jr; 1 box (Box 735)
    MC104-99A
  - Soviet Science: An Evaluation, (The United States and the Soviet Union 2), 1958 May 6; Gaither, Rowan H., Jr; Turkevich, John, 1907-1998; 1 box (Box 735)
    MC104-99B
  - An Appraisal of Soviet and American Propaganda, 1958 May 22; Allen, George V. (George Venable), 1903-1970; Kirk, Grayson L.; 1 box (Box 735)
    MC104-100A
  - Report on Algeria, 1958 May 26; Trager, Frank N.; Yazid, M'hammed; 1 box (Box 735)
    MC104-100B
  - Canadian-American Foreign Policy, 1958 June 4; Armstrong, Hamilton Fish, 1893-1973; Smith, Sidney E.; 1 box (Box 735)
    MC104-101A
  - Untitled, 1958 June 6; McElroy, Neil H.; Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich), 1908-1979; 1 box (Box 735)
    MC104-101B
  - Problems of German Unification, 1958 June 17; Heuss, Theodor; McCloy, John J. (John Jay), 1895-1989; 1 box (Box 735)
    MC104-102A
  - Untitled, 1958 June 24; Charles E. Bohlen; Garcia, Carlos P.; 1 box (Box 735)
    MC104-102B
  - Principal Developments in the Eastern Block since the Death of Stalin, undated; 1 box (Box 735)
    MC104-103A
  - The Development of United States Military Strategy, 1959 March 9; Spofford, Charles M.; Taylor, Maxwell D. (Maxwell Davenport), 1901-1987; 1 box (Box 735)
    MC104-103B
  - The Multinational Corporation, 1970 November 11; Billington, James H.; Rockefeller, David, 1915-2017; 1 box (Box 735)
    MC104-104.1
  - The Multinational Corporation, 1970 November 11; Billington, James H.; Rockefeller, David, 1915-2017; 1 box (Box 735)
    MC104-104.2
  - A New Multi-Polar Balance: Illusion or Reality, The Balance of Power, Russell C. Leffingwell Lectures, 1972 March 29; Buchan, Alastair; Manning, Bayless; 1 box (Box 735)
    MC104-105
  - The Balance of Power: Theory or Practice, The Balance of Power, Russel C. Leffingwell Lectures, 1972 April 6; Buchan, Alastair; Norstad, General Lauris; 1 box (Box 736)
    MC104-106
  - The Balance of the Future, 1972 April 13; Bowie, Robert R., (Robert Richardson) 1909-2013; Buchan, Alastair; 1 box (Box 736)
    MC104-107
  - German-American Dialogue, The Changing Pattern of American-European Relationship, 1972 April 17; Bator, Francis M., 1925-; Bowie, Robert R., (Robert Richardson) 1909-2013; Pauls, Rolf; 1 box (Box 736)
    MC104-108
  - 50th Anniversary Dinner, 1972 September 28; Manning, Bayless; McCloy, John J. (John Jay), 1895-1989; Rockefeller, David, 1915-2017; Rogers, William P.; Waldheim, Kurt; 1 box (Box 736)
    MC104-109
  - Does Technology Make the Concept of National Interest Obsolete? The Mutual Impact of Science and a World Society, the Elihu Root Lectures, 1972 October 26; Brooks, Harvey; Rockefeller, David, 1915-2017; 1 box (Box 736)
    MC104-110
  - National Public Radio, Nuclear Proliferation, 1976 June 11; Agnew, Harold M.; Kahan, Jerome H.; Kennedy, Richard; Norman, Barbara; Taylor, Theodore B., 1925-; 1 box (Box 736)
    MC104-111
  - American Defense; Old Fears, etc, 1976 December 13; Frye, Alton; Kraar, Louis; Warnke, Paul C. (Paul Culliton), 1920-2001; 1 box (Box 736)
    MC104-112
  - National Public Radio, Arms Control, 1977 June 17; Cahn, Anne H.; Newman, Barbara; Pierre, Andrew J.; 1 box (Box 736)
    MC104-113
  - The United Kingdom and the International Economy, Leffingwell Lecture, 1977 November 29; Lord, Winston; Richardson, Gordon; 1 box (Box 736)
    MC104-114
  - National Public Radio, European Security and the Future of NATO, 1978 February 28; Burt, Richard; Enzor, David; Goodby, James E.; Siena, James; Stratton, Samuel; 1 box (Box 736)
    MC104-115.1
    Program ends after 54 minutes, 30 seconds; restarted after 1 minute, 50 seconds.
  - National Public Radio, European Security and the Future of NATO, 1978 February 28; Burt, Richard; Enzor, David; Goodby, James E.; Siena, James; Stratton, Samuel; 1 box (Box 736)
    MC104-115.2
    Audio begins abruptly.
  - Eurocommunism after the French Election, Eurocommunism #1, CFR, 1978 April 3; Hoffman, Stanley; 1 box (Box 736)
    MC104-116
  - Eurocommunisim: Hope or Threat for the West, 1978 April 28; Campbell, John C.; Semple, Robert B. Jr; Toquesh, Rudolph; Tuckerman, Anne; 1 box (Box 736)
    MC104-117
    Born digital.; Waters, Mike; Fredrick, Pauline
  - The National Security Today, 1978 September 13; Brown, Harold, 1927-2019; 1 box (Box 736)
    MC104-118
    Recording of roundtable discussion for broadcast on NPR radio.
  - International Economic and Monetary Outlook, 1978 November 13; Bergsten, C. Fred., 1941-; 1 box (Box 736)
    MC104-119
    Long drop out after 2:57 for 3:30.
  - The Dollar, Past and Future (John J. McCloy Lecture), 1978 November 15; Triffin, Robert; 1 box (Box 737)
    MC104-120
  - World Hunger: Is There an Answer? Meeting for Members and Spouses, 1978 December 4; Linowitz, Sol M., 1913-2005; 1 box (Box 737)
    MC104-121
  - Stories and History, 1978 December 21; Berger, Marilyn; Lord, Winston; White, Theodore H.; 1 box (Box 737)
    MC104-122
  - The Yen in United States-Japanese Economic Relations, 1979 January 8; Fisher, Richard W.; Gyōten, Toyoo, 1931-; 1 box (Box 737)
    MC104-123
  - American Foreign Policy: A Legislative View, Elihu Root Lecture, 1979 January 23; Fulbright, J. William; McPherson, Harry.; 1 box (Box 737)
    MC104-124
  - A Conversation with the Senator, 1979 February 14; Hauser, Rita E.; Moynihan, Daniel P. (Daniel Patrick), 1927-2003; 1 box (Box 737)
    MC104-125
  - Cuban Foreign Ministry, 1979 February 22; Roa, Raul, Jr.; 1 box (Box 737)
    MC104-126
  - The Energy Situation: An Overview, 1979 February 27; Schlesinger, J. R.; 1 box (Box 737)
    MC104-127
  - Soft Energy Paths, 1979 March 5; Lovins, A.; 1 box (Box 737)
    MC104-128
  - United States-Chinese Relations: Past, Present and Future, Special Corporation Service Meeting, 1979 March 13; Lord, Winston; Morse, Kenneth P.; 1 box (Box 737)
    MC104-129
  - Present Reflections, 1979 March 19; Rusk, Dean, 1909-1994; Sisco, Joseph J.; 1 box (Box 737)
    MC104-130
    Tape ends abruptly at beginning of question and answer session.
  - Great Power Relations After Indochina, 1979 April 2; Kennedy, E. M.; 1 box (Box 737)
    MC104-131
  - SALT and American Security: Three Perspectives, 1979 May 24; Gumbleton, T.; Warnke, Paul C. (Paul Culliton), 1920-2001; Zumwalt, E.; 1 box (Box 738)
    MC104-132
  - Reflections on the Current Scene, 1979 May 31; Kissinger, Henry, 1923-; 1 box (Box 738)
    MC104-133
  - Conversation with the Foreign Secretary, 1979 September 24; Lord Carrington; 1 box (Box 738)
    MC104-134
  - Towards a Multipolar World: Issues and Opportunities, 1979 September 26; François-Poncet, Jean, 1928-2012; 1 box (Box 738)
    MC104-135
  - Iran, 1979 October 2; Yazdī, Ibrāhīm; 1 box (Box 738)
    MC104-136
  - Managing the Economy: The Limitations of Government, Russel C. Leffingwell Lectures, 1979 October 11; Healey, Denis; 1 box (Box 738)
    MC104-137
  - Managing the Economy: The Domestic Balance, Russell C. Leffingwell Lectures, 1979 October 15; Healey, Denis; 1 box (Box 738)
    MC104-138
  - Managing the Economy: The International Dimension, Russell C. Leffingwell Lectures, 1979 October 18; Healey, Denis; 1 box (Box 738)
    MC104-139
  - The Dollar at Home and Abroad, 1979 November 5; Volcker, Paul A.; 1 box (Box 738)
    MC104-140
    Paul A. Volcker (1927-) is an economist who has served in several prominent positions in the federal government. Born in Cape May, NJ, Volcker attended Princeton University for his undergraduate education, graduating summa cum laude in 1949. He went on to earn a master's degree in political economy and government from Harvard University in 1951, then studied at the London School of Economics in 1951-1952 under the Rotary Foundation's Ambassadorial Scholarships program. Volcker began his career in government service in 1952 as an economist at the Federal Reserve Bank of New York. Five years later, in 1957, he left the position to join the private sector, taking a job at Chase Manhattan Bank. Volcker first worked for the Treasury Department in 1962 as the director of the Office of Financial Analysis, and the following year became the deputy undersecretary for monetary affairs. He resumed work in the private sector once more in 1965, returning to Chase Manhattan Bank as vice president and director of planning. Volcker served as undersecretary of the Treasury for international monetary affairs from 1969-1974. In this capacity, Volcker was influential in the Nixon administration's economic policy changes of August 1971. These policy changes, particularly the suspension of the U.S. dollar's convertibility to gold and a short-term freeze on wages and prices, temporarily halted inflation and increased the rates of employment and productivity in the United States. After leaving the Treasury Department, Volcker returned to the Federal Reserve Bank of New York from 1975-1979 to serve as its president. In August 1979, Jimmy Carter appointed Volcker as chairman of the Board of Governors for the Federal Reserve. The Federal Reserve under Volcker's leadership is credited with ending the inflation of the 1970s through aggressive control of the money supply, leading to historically high interest rates. By the end his term, the inflation process had ended, giving rise to years of stable growth. As chairman, Volcker also put more focus on the economic conditions in developing countries and prohibiting certain activities of commercial banks. After leaving the Board of Governors in 1987, Volcker served as chair of the National Commission on Public Service. The following year, he became chairman of Wolfensohn and Co., a boutique international investment banking firm. Volcker was chairman of the Board of Trustees of the International Accounting Standards from 2000-2005. In 1996, Volcker was asked by representatives of the Swiss and Jewish communities to head an effort to trace accounts of victims of Nazi persecution opened in Swiss banks before World War II, leading to substantial compensation for survivors and their progeny. In 2004, the Secretary General of the United Nations called upon Volcker to undertake an investigation of allegations of substantial corruption by participants in the U.N.'s Oil for Food program and within the U.N. itself. That successful investigation led to a further request by the president of the World Bank to lead a review of the Bank's anti-corruption program, prompting substantial reforms in Bank procedures. Volcker headed President Obama's Economic Recovery Advisory Board from 2009 to 2011. In this role, he crafted the "Volcker Rule," a provision to the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act of 2010. The provision restricts banking institutions in the United States from conducting certain kinds of speculative investment activities. Volcker was a senior fellow in the Woodrow Wilson School of Public and International Affairs at Princeton University for the 1974-1975 academic year. He is the coauthor of several books. For many years he chaired the Trilateral Commission and the "Group of 30," consisting of leading central bankers, other financial officials, and financial scholars.
  - The United Nations – Is It Relevant?, 1979 November 8; McHenry, Donald F.; 1 box (Box 738)
    MC104-141
  - The Missing Alternative in the United States – Soviet Union Relations, 1979 December 3; Shulman, Marshall D., 1916-2007; 1 box (Box 738)
    MC104-142
  - The People of Cambodia: What Can Be Done?, 1979 December 12; Carter, Rosalynn S.; 1 box (Box 738)
    MC104-143
  - A Conversation with Walter Cronkite, Sons and Daughters Meeting, 1979 December 19; Cronkite, Walter; 1 box (Box 739)
    MC104-144
  - Persian Gulf Policy, 1980 March 6; Brown, Harold, 1927-2019; 1 box (Box 739)
    MC104-145
  - North/South Relations: The Findings of the Brandt Commission, 1980 February 11; Brandt, Willy, 1913-1992.; 1 box (Box 739)
    MC104-146
    Tape ends at beginning of question and answer session.
  - The Foreign Policy of Texas, 1980 April 28; Clements, William P., 1917-2011; 1 box (Box 739)
    MC104-147
  - Oil and the Decline of the West, 1980 May 1; Levy, Walter James, 1911-1997; 1 box (Box 739)
    MC104-148
  - Role of Congress in American Foreign Policy, 1980 May 19; Brademas, John, 1927-2016; 1 box (Box 739)
    MC104-149
  - Critical Issues in United States' Foreign Policy, 1980 May 28; Christopher, Warren; 1 box (Box 739)
    MC104-150
  - United States-China Relations, 1980 September 23; Woodcock, Leonard; 1 box (Box 739)
    MC104-151
  - Toward a New Western Partnership?, 1980 September 29; François-Poncet, Jean, 1928-2012; 1 box (Box 739)
    MC104-152
  - International Trade: A View from New York State, 1980 November 6; Carey, Hugh; 1 box (Box 739)
    MC104-153
  - Election Mandate for United States' Foreign Policy, 1980 November 6; Young, Andrew, 1932-; 1 box (Box 739)
    MC104-154
  - Early Reflections on the Reagan Administration, 1980 December 3; Buckley, William F., Jr., 1925-2008; 1 box (Box 739)
    MC104-155
  - Europe and the United States: Old Friends in a Changing Relationship, 1980 September 22; Lord Carrington; 1 box (Box 740)
    MC104-156A
  - Political and Strategic Consequences of Economic Development, 1979 January 3; Fraser, Malcolm; 1 box (Box 740)
    MC104-156B
  - Soviet-American Relations: The Imperatives of Mutual Restraint, 1980 September 24; Anderson, John B. (John Bayard), 1922-2017; 1 box (Box 740)
    MC104-157A
  - Untitled, undated; Jones, David C., 1921-2013; 1 box (Box 740)
    MC104-157B
  - The United States' International Competitive Position: Its Decline and What We Could Do About It, 1980 December 8; Peterson, Peter G.; 1 box (Box 740)
    MC104-158
  - National Security 1977-1980: A Summing Up, 1980 December 18; Brown, Harold, 1927-2019; 1 box (Box 740)
    MC104-159
  - A Conversation with Henry Kissinger, 1980 December 19; Brinkley, David; Kissinger, Henry, 1923-; 1 box (Box 740)
    MC104-160
  - National Security and the Navy Today and Tomorrow, 1981 January 29; Hayward, Thomas Bibb, 1924-; 1 box (Box 740)
    MC104-161
  - Canada-United States Relations, 1981 February 4; MacGuigan, Mark, 1931-1998; 1 box (Box 740)
    MC104-162
  - Iran: Did We Fail?, 1981 February 17; Kennedy, Moorhead, Jr; Tomseth, Victor; 1 box (Box 740)
    MC104-163
  - Thoughts on Transition, 1981 February 18; McCloy, John J. (John Jay), 1895-1989; 1 box (Box 740)
    MC104-164
  - The Caribbean: A View from Florida, 1981 February 24; Graham, Robert; 1 box (Box 740)
    MC104-165
  - United States Foreign Policy: Alternative Approaches to Human Rights, 1981 March 10; Kirkpatrick, Jeane J.; 1 box (Box 740)
    MC104-166
  - Congress and United States Foreign Policy: The War Powers Resolution, Elihu Root Lecture - Number 1, 1981 April 6; Javits, Jacob K. (Jacob Koppel), 1904-1986; 1 box (Box 740)
    MC104-167
  - Congress and United States Foreign Policy: Normalization of Relations with China, Elihu Root Lecture - Number 2, 1981 April 9; Javits, Jacob K. (Jacob Koppel), 1904-1986; 1 box (Box 740)
    MC104-168
  - Congress and United States Foreign Policy: Less Developed Countries, Elihu Root Lectures, 1981 April 13; Javits, Jacob K. (Jacob Koppel), 1904-1986; 1 box (Box 741)
    MC104-169
  - Is United States' Intelligence Adequate?, 1981 April 20; Turner, Stansfield, 1923-2018; 1 box (Box 741)
    MC104-170
  - NATO's Defense in an Era of Global Challenge, 1981 April 29; Rogers, Bernard W.; 1 box (Box 741)
    MC104-171
    Drop out at 26:42 for about 30 seconds.
  - Conversation with David Stockman, 1981 May 20; Stockman, David; 1 box (Box 741)
    MC104-172
  - Foreign Policy Dilemmas of the 80s, 1981 May 27; Brzeziński, Zbigniew (1928-2017).; 1 box (Box 741)
    MC104-173
  - Immigration and Refugee Policy, 1981 June 9; Hesburgh, Theodore; 1 box (Box 741)
    MC104-174
  - Food: A Tool in International Relations, 1981 June 10; Block, John R.; 1 box (Box 741)
    MC104-175
  - A Conversation with Caspar Weinberger on Defense Strategy, 1981 June 17; Weinberger, Caspar W.; 1 box (Box 741)
    MC104-176
  - A Conversation with President Anwar El-Sadat, 1981 August 7; El-Sadat, Mohamed Anwar; 1 box (Box 741)
    MC104-177
    No introduction of speaker. Brief dropout at 13:55. Tape ends at beginning of question and answer session, with a quick blip of sound following program cut off.
  - Creating a United States Policy to the Third World, 1981 September 14; Rockefeller, David, 1915-2017; 1 box (Box 741)
    MC104-178
  - Current German Political Issues, 1981 October 13; Kohl, Helmut, 1930-2017.; 1 box (Box 741)
    MC104-179
    Speech in German
  - The Future of Strategic Arms Limitation, 1981 October 20; Rostow, Eugene V. (Eugene Victor), 1913-2002; 1 box (Box 741)
    MC104-180
    Drop out after 44:37.
  - United States – European Relations in the '80s, New Members' Meeting and Dinner, 1981 November 30; Eagleburger, Lawrence S.; 1 box (Box 741)
    MC104-181
  - United States Trade Policy and the Export-Import Bank, 1981 December 2; Draper, William; 1 box (Box 742)
    MC104-182
  - Current Issues in the Middle East, 1981 December 8; Peres, Shimʿon 1923-2016; 1 box (Box 742)
    MC104-183
  - The Dangerous Decade, 1982 January 6; Jones, David C., 1921-2013; 1 box (Box 742)
    MC104-184
  - Implications of the Jamaican Recovery for Policy, 1982 January 12; Seaga, Edward P. G.; 1 box (Box 742)
    MC104-185
  - Arms Sales in a Troubled World, 1982 February 2; Pierre, Andrew J.; 1 box (Box 742)
    MC104-186
  - International Implications of Polish Crisis, 1982 February 8; Brzeziński, Zbigniew (1928-2017).; 1 box (Box 742)
    MC104-187
  - The Alliance and Nuclear Weapons, 1982 March 17; Burt, Richard; 1 box (Box 742)
    MC104-188
    Drop out at 29:00
  - Strategy, Dollars and Sense, 1982 April 29; Komer, Robert; 1 box (Box 742)
    MC104-189
    After a drop out at the end of first segment there is a short section which sounds like the end of another session.
  - Cameroon and the United States, 1982 June 29; Ahidjo, Ahmadou, 1924-1989; 1 box (Box 742)
    MC104-190
    Level drops at times making the audio hard to understand.
  - The Capacity of the United Nations for Keeping the Peace, 1982 September 20; Pérez de Cuéllar, Javier, 1920-; 1 box (Box 742)
    MC104-191
  - The Role of the World Bank in the 1980s, 1982 September 23; Clausen, A.W.; 1 box (Box 742)
    MC104-192
  - The New Arms Control Agenda, 1982 October 18; Hart, Gary, 1936-; 1 box (Box 742)
    MC104-193
  - Critical Changes in International Trade Policy, 1982 October 26; Strauss, Robert; 1 box (Box 742)
    MC104-194
    26 seconds of blank space at 28:18.
  - The Politics of Central Europe, 1982 November 8; Owen, David; 1 box (Box 742)
    MC104-195
  - Current Status of I.N.F. Negotiations, 1982 December 9; Nitze, Paul; 1 box (Box 742)
    MC104-196
  - Reagan's START Proposal: Formula for Stability, 1983 January 18; Rowny, Edward L., 1917-2017; 1 box (Box 742)
    MC104-197
    Speaker off-mic on purpose; drop out at 29:24 for 12 seconds.
  - A New Priority for Trade, 1983 March 2; Brock, William Emerson, 1930-; 1 box (Box 742)
    MC104-198
    Drop out at 25:10 for 1 minute, 10 seconds.
  - Strategic Nuclear Forces and United States Foreign Policy, 1983 April 6; Scowcroft, Brent; 1 box (Box 742)
    MC104-199
  - The Present Political Scene in El Salvador and Central America, 1985 December 19; Duarte, José Napoleón; Peterson, Peter G.; 1 box (Box 743)
    MC104-200
    [Access is restricted for 25 years from the date of the meeting.]
  - The Third World Challenge to United States Foreign Policy, 1983 May 25; Feinberg, Richard E.; Gardner, Richard N.; 1 box (Box 743)
    MC104-201
  - United States Response to the Crisis in Central America, 1983 September 15; Cranston, Alan; Palmieri, Victor H.; 1 box (Box 743)
    MC104-202
    Drop out after 22:32 for 56 seconds.
  - Some Observations on the Situation in the Middle East, 1983 September 29; Mubarak, Mohamed Hosni; 1 box (Box 743)
    MC104-203
  - Current Defense Issues, 1983 October 5; Vessey, John William, 1922-2016; 1 box (Box 743)
    MC104-204
    Drop out after 27:36 for 2 minutes. The end of a different program can be heard after the conclusion of the Vessey meeting.
  - The Status of the West Bank: the Continuing Israeli Dilemma, 1983 October 24; Schocken, Gershom; 1 box (Box 743)
    MC104-205
  - Global Interdependence and Science, 1983 November 1; Thomas, Lewis, 1913-1993; 1 box (Box 743)
    MC104-206.1
    Side one ends abruptly, side two begins abruptly, ends at beginning of question and answer session.
    Lewis Thomas, M.D., noted physician, scientist, and author, was born on November 25, 1913, to Joseph S. and Grace Emma (Peck) Thomas in Flushing, New York, where his father, a surgeon, had a medical practice. After four very successful years in high school, he entered Princeton University at the age of fifteen. Thomas's first three years at Princeton, however, were desultory at best, until his senior year when a biology course sparked his interest. He received a B.S. from Princeton in 1933 and entered Harvard Medical School, graduating Cum Laude in 1937. The next two years were spent as an intern at Boston City Hospital (1937-1939), and another two as a resident in neurology at Columbia's Neurological Institute (1939-1941).